Shuai Zhou

UX DESIGNER

shuaizhou487@gmail.com 917-545-2916 shuai.design

I'm a UX designer with 6 years working experience in building enterprise and consumer software products. I'm currently employed as UX Designer for digital design user experience team in AT&T. I am responsible for delivering solutions to AT&T clients. By collaborating with product owners, designers, and developers on daily basis. Over the years, I have acquired a solid expertise in several project management methodologies and built up experience leading agile teams. Authorized to work in the US for any employer.

Education

Harrisburg University of Science and Technology, Harrisburg, PA

01/2017 - Present

Master of Science in Project Management

University of Cincinnati, Cincinnati, OH

08/2012 - 12/2015

Master of Design in User Experience Design

Hubei Institute of Fine Arts, Wuhan, China

09/2007 - 06/2011

Bachelor of Art in Textile Design

Experience

UX DESIGNER in AT&T, Dallas, TX

01/2017 - Present

Working in the Digital Design User Experience team, collaborating with the product team, business team and development team in an Agile/Scrum workflow to design visually-compelling and highly-usable web applications product for AT&T B2B. The product were used by all AT&T's business clients.

- Lead the redesign for AT&T Business Center Homepage, solved more than 200% page traffic problems.
- Designed AT&T online buy experience, brought million dollars for business.
- Designed tens of projects for AT&T Business Digital Product.

UX DESIGNER in TourConnect, Frisco, TX

04/2016 - 12/2016

As the only user experience designer in TourConnect worked with development teams to create an engaging online tour industry community platform. Collected requirements from clients and conducted focus group to discover user needs, found the way to enhance the functionality and usability for product.

- Designed a new onboarding experience for user, increased 5% onboarding success rate.
- Designed e-contract management tool, solved user's requirements.

UX DESIGNER INTERN in Hospital Communications Inc, Cincinnati, OH

05/2015 - 09/2015

As a Internship UX designer on the Hospital Communications Inc (HCI), leaded by VP of sales and worked with the development team to redesign the health care TV application. The application applied on all Hospital Communications Inc TV products.

- Redesigned the health care TV application experience, dramatically increased customer satisfaction.
- Created design components system for the health care TV application.

UX/UI DESIGNER in Sohu Inc, Beijing, China

12/2013 - 12/2014

As a user experience and user interface designer for the mobile design team at the Sohu Inc. Worked with the design team and development team in an agile development environment to design mockups and wireframes for applications and websites. Created interactive interfaces by working with developers to ensure an application adheres to the Sohu business requirements and user-friendly.

- Prototyped visual design concepts and friendly interactive to provide solution for mobile applications, resulting in a better user experience.
- Produced flow charts, wireframes and designed page layouts for the mobile application.
- Created and documented patterns for visual systems.
- Responsible for designing and developing mobile web pages in a fast-paced environment.

GRAPHIC DESIGNER INTERN in Michelman, Cincinnati, OH

05/2013 - 08/2013

As a graphic designer worked for Marketing department in for Michelman Inc. Designed and produced catalogs, sales sheets, proposals, scenario illustrations, brochures, posters, custom displays for trade shows and in-house exhibits and all other items.

- Actively researched industry trends to bring new ideas and applications to company.
- Collaborated with marketing personnel in development of product information.
- Created sales collateral, marketing literature and print ads.

GRADUATE ASSISTANT in University Of Cincinnati, Cincinnati, OH

01/2013 - 12/2015

As a graduate assistant worked with Associate Professor Renee Seward in the See Word Reading App. See Word Reading® is a personalized, fun & effective platform for students to learn early literacy skills through a suite of two applications a teacher app and student app.

- Gathered user data through methods such as participatory user interview, user testing, and analytics reporting and utilized that data to identify and prioritise Pain Points.
- Developed sketches and wireframes for teams, introduced new tools, Sketch App, to enable effective online collaboration and deliverables.

TEACHING ASSISTANT in University Of Cincinnati, Cincinnati, OH

08/2012 - 12/2013

As a teaching assistant worked with Associate Professor Fernandez Oscar in the Design History Course.

• Developed trust and rapport with students, provided assistance to teachers and engaged students in learning activities and positive behaviors to optimize their understanding of lessons.

Skills

UI/UX design, Interaction Design, Motion Graphics, Visual Design, Illustration, Prototyping, Wireframing, Storyboards, Style Guides, Visual Mockups, Responsive Design

Link

http://shuai.design/ https://www.linkedin.com/in/shuai-zhou-898729b2/

Additional Information

TOOLS & PROGRAMMING: Adobe Creative Suite, Microsoft Office, Sketch, InVision, Axure, Lucidchart, Zeplin, Jira, HTML5, CSS3, jQuery.

REFERENCES: Upon request.